Guide to the Oral History of the American Left Collection OH.002
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Oral History of the American Left Main Series, 1940-2011
  - Esta Nette, 1978; cuid1410 (Box 10, Box 21, Cd Nette 1)
    One 1978 interview covering the history of the Pioneers, the Young Communist League, and protests.
  - Esta Nette, undated; cuid1411 (Box 21, Dvd Nette 2, Box 10)
    One DVD interview covering the history of the Pioneers, the Young Communist League, and protests.
  - Demosthenes Nicas, Circa 1987-1989; cuid1412 (Box 10, Cassette 416 A-D, Box 21, Cd Nicas 1-4)
    Nicas discusses activities from 1900 through the late 1930s, including the relationship between the CIO and Communist Party in Ohio, newspapers, and the impact of the Hitler-Stalin pact.
  - Demosthenes Nicas, 1986; cuid1413 (Box 10, Cassette 417, Box 21, Cd Nicas 5-6)
    Speech on Greek labor and radicalism.
  - Rose Nobel, Feb 28, 1981; cuid1414 (Box 21, Cd Nobel 1-2, Box 10, Cassette 385 A-B)
  - Joseph and Ruth Norrick, Mar 15, 1983; cuid1415 (Box 6, Cassette 174 A-D, Box 8, Folder 13, Box 21, Cd Norrick 1-2)
    The interview covers origins of radicalism in Indiana coal mining traditions during the 1910s-1920s, Joseph Norrick's role in 1930s-1940s Left, and perspectives on problems of "Americanizing" Communism in the United States. Ruth Norrick discusses her background in Terre Haute, Indiana, meeting with Eugene Debs, literary life in New York during the 1930s, Cold War-era blacklisting from United Nations Children's agency, and her work in journalism.
    Related Archival Materials
    Additional content from Joseph and Ruth Norrick was recorded on the second cassette of the Jose Alvarez interview in the Oral History of the American Left (OH 002).
  - Clarence Norris, Feb 25, 1981; cuid1416 (Box 21, Cd Norris 1, Box 6, Cassette 175)
    Interview documents the Scottsboro Boys case, as recalled by one of nine defendants. Interview also covers the role of International Labor Defense and NAACP and the circumstances of his pardon.
  - Paul Novick, 1979; cuid1417 (Box 21, Cd Novick 1, Box 10, Cassette 401)
    Interview includes discussion of the Morgen Freiheit and Yiddish literature.
    Interview by Paul Buhle
  - Paul Novick, Jan 20, 1983; cuid1418 (Box 21, Cd Novick 2, Box 6, Cassette 176)
    Discussion of Yiddish culture and politics including his employment by the Groysser Kundes magazine as a humorist and his involvement with the Morgen Freiheit, which he joined in 1922 and edited from 1939-1988.
  - Paul Novick, Feb 9, 1985; cuid1419 (Box 10, Cassette 402, Box 21, Cd Novick 3)
  - Stanley Nowak, Mar 30, 1983; cuid1420 (Box 6, Cassette 177 A-C, Box 8, Folder 14, Box 21, Cd Nowak 1-3)
    Interview documents the Polish-American Left in Detroit during the 1930s, cigar workers, the United Auto Workers, the American Slav Congress, different Polish-American Left organizations from the 1910s-1920s, and Poland in the 1980s. Only third disk of Nowak interview has been transcribed.
  - Marjorie O'Brien, May 7, 1983; cuid1421 (Box 21, Cd O'Brien 1, Box 6, Cassette 178)
    O'Brien discusses her background in Wisconsin, the University of Wisconsin Trotskyist circle, activities in the 1940s, and her attitude towards C.L.R. James and Johnson-Forest Tendency.
  - Harvey O'Connor, Sep 27, 1977; cuid1422 (Box 21, Cd O'Connor 1-3, Box 8, Folder 15, Box 6, Cassette 180 A-C)
    Interview documents O'Connor's activities in Seattle around time of 1919 general strike, his work in the Federated Press during the 1920s-40s, relationships with Communists and oldtime labor editors and ethnic radicals such as Ludwig Lore, activities in Pittsburgh during the 1930s, and the attack of the House Un-American Activities Committee during the 1950s.
  - Edna Ocko, 1981; cuid1423 (Box 21, Cd Ocko 1, Box 6, Cassette 181)
    Interview analyzes the relationship between the Left and dance in the 1930s-1940s, looking at form and content in radicalism and modern dance.
  - Hugo Oehler, Jul 6, 1977; cuid1424 (Box 21, Cd Oehler 1-4, Box 6, Cassette 179 A-B)
    Interview covers Oehler's philosophical background and introduction to Marx, his involvement with the Communist Party, including organization through trade unions and undercover activities within CP on behalf of Trotskyites. Oehler further analyzes the struggles between Stalin and Trotsky supporters and discusses his activities in Spanish Civil War and opinions on French Turn.
  - Margaret O'Hara, Apr 22, 1980; cuid1425 (Box 21, Cd O'Hara 1, Box 81, Cassette 380)
  - Gene O'Hare, undated; cuid1426 (Box 21, Cd O'Hare 1-4, Box 6, Cassette 182 A-B)
    Interview by Victoria O'Hare Von Hagen
  - Bertell Ollman, Nov 5, 1982; cuid1427 (Box 80, Cassette 349-350, Box 21, Cd Ollman 1-2)
    Interview covers Ollman's background in Milwaukee in the 1940s-1950s, radicalism in Madison, Wisconsin, his political activities and intellectual growth in Madison Students League for Industrial Democracy, Students for Democratic Action, and his reflections on the Madison experience.
  - Celia Orlansky, Oct 27, 1981; cuid1428 (Box 21, Cd Orlansky 1-2, Box 80, Cassette 351-352)
  - Myra Page, 1982; cuid1429 (Box 21, Cd Page 1-2, Box 6, Cassette 183 A-B)
    Myra Page was a Southern writer and novelist who authored The Gathering Storm and Moscow Yankee during the 1930s.
  - John Pandera, Oct 22, 1982; cuid1430 (Box 6, Cassette 184, Box 21, Cd Pandera 1)
    Pandera discusses the Left in the South Slav sections of San Pedro, California during the 1930s-1950s.
  - Morris Pasternak, Mar 21, 1978; cuid1431 (Box 21, Cd Pasternak 1, Box 10, Cassette 381)
    Interview by Marvin Gettleman.
  - Louise Thompson Patterson, Nov 16, 1981- Nov 30, 1981; cuid1432 (Box 8, Folder 16, Box 6, Cassette 185 A-E, Box 22, Cd Patterson 1-5)
    Thompson discusses her youth in Sacramento California, her move to New York City, life in Harlem during the 1920s-1930s, and the Scottsboro case in the 1930s.
  - Pearl, Feb 22, 1982; cuid1433 (Box 79, Cassette 296 A-B, Box 22, Cd Pearl 1-2)
    Interview includes a discussion of Pearl's youth, her relationship with her mother, her mother's influence on her outlook, and her Panamanian/West Indian heritage. She also discusses work in a textile factory while at school, and a brief period in domestic work on Park Avenue in New York. Interview includes her philosophies on activism and struggle. She describes becoming an activist during the 1930s and joining the Communist Party. She also discusses Party actions and CP activity within the needle trades union. Pearl analyzes the nature of conflict within Communist Party leadership, particularly with relation to race and gender. She compares the difference between socialist approach and the CP approach. She concludes with thoughts on feminism, critiques of the Soviet Union, and friendship and family in the CP movement.
    Duration: 63 minutes; Preservation Note: One of the audiocassettes could not be digitized due to its condition.
  - Albert Perocco, Jan 19, 1968; cuid1434 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    Perocco discusses the Bridgeport, Connecticut Socialist Party and Jasper McLevy as Socialist mayor.
  - Elaine Perry, Mar 26, 1979; cuid1435 (Box 6, Cassette 187 A-B, Box 22, Cd Perry 1-2)
    Perry discusses women's role in the electrical industry in New Jersey during World War II and the activities of the National Negro Congress. She also discusses the United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers of America (UE) and the International Union of Electronic, Electrical, Salaried, Machine and Furniture Workers (IUE) and provides general reflections.
  - Irja M. Peters, Jul 30, 1983; cuid1436 (Box 22, Cd Peters 1-2, Box 6, Cassette 188 A-B)
    Peters describes growing up in Finnish-American left of the 1930s in Mesabi Range, her unhappy marriage to non-Finnish intellectual, and her return to her "roots."
  - Sam Pevzner, Sep 24, 1978; cuid1437 (Box 22, Cd Pevzner 2, Box 10, Cassette 403)
  - Sam Pevzner, Jun 26, 1983; cuid1438 (Box 6, Cassette 189, Box 22, Cd Pevzner 1)
    Pevzner discusses experiences in the Pennsylvania International Workers Order (IWO), his background as a Jewish entertainer, his political conversion, and activities within the sphere of the Yiddishe Kultur Farband (YKUF).
  - Utah Phillips, undated; cuid1439 (Box 22, Cd Phillips 1, Box 6, Cassette 190)
    Recording of the IWW folk singer recalling experiences from 1940s to 1980s on a WBJC (Baltimore) radio broadcast.
  - Marge Piercy, Apr 1979; cuid1440 (Box 79, Cassette 297, Box 22, Cd Piercy 1)
  - Rose Podmaka, Jan 22, 1979 - Mar 19, 1979; cuid1441 (Box 8, Folder 18, Box 22, Cd Podmaka 1-2, Box 6, Cassette 191 A-B)
    Podmaka discusses her background in coal and steel region of Ohio and West Virginia during the 1930s, experiences at the United Electrical Workers-Hatfield Wire & Cable in New Jersey during the 1940s, and the relationship between the UE and the Association of Catholic Trade Unionists.
  - Rose Podmaka, Oct 27, 1979; cuid1442 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Ira Polansky, Nov 26, 2002; cuid1443 (Box 6, Cassette 192.1, Box 22, Cd Polansky 1)
    Interview with a program director for Camp Kinderland documents Jewish political and cultural life and includes discussion of activities at the camp and childhood in the Coops, a radical housing complex in the Bronx.
    Interview by Daniel Weber.
    A transcript of the Ira Polansky interview can be found in the Communist Party of the United States of America Records (TAM 132).
  - Justine Polier, Jun 22, 1982; cuid1444 (Box 22, Cd Polier 1, Box 6, Cassette 192)
    Interview covers Polier's recollections of legal work during the 1930s and the origins of National Lawyers' Guild.
    Interview by Ann Ginger.
  - Popular Front Culture, Dec 1977; cuid1445 (Box 22, Cd Popular Front Culture 1-3, Box 6, Cassette 193 A-C)
    Discussion led by Paul Buhle. Includes A.B. Magil, Steve Max, Steve Nelson, Nat Cohen and others, about the meaning of "culture" to younger generation in the Popular Front; attitudes toward sports, particularly baseball in the Left and in the Daily Worker; and neighborhood activity around cultural themes in New York.
  - Pearl Zeluck Porterfield, May 7, 1983; cuid1446 (Box 22, Cd Porterfield 1, Box 6, Cassette 194)
    Interview covering the Johnson-Forest Tendency and the activities of the Workers Party during the 1940s.
  - Albert Prago: Collection of lectures from the course "The Spanish Civil War and its International Impact", Oct 20, 1981-Dec 8, 1981; cuid1447 (Box 6, Cassette 195 A-N, Box 22, Cd Prago 1-20)
    A collection of lectures from a Albert Prago-coordinated course entitled "The Spanish Civil War and its International Impact," held at the New School for Social Research in the fall of 1981. The lecturers were: Albert Prago (Oct 20, 1981, CD Prago 1-2), John Gerassi (Oct 27, 1981, CD Prago 3-5), Carl Marzani (Nov 3, 1981, CD Prago 6-8), Dante Puzzo (Nov 10, 1981, CD Prago 9-11), Victor Rabinowitz and Albert Prago (Nov 17, 1981, CD Prago 12-14), Maury Colow and Carl Geiser (Nov 24, 1981, CD Prago 15-17), Pete Seeger (Dec 1, 1981, Prago 18-20), and Albert Prago (Dec 8, 1981, CD Prago 20).
  - Albert Prago, Mar 20, 1991; cuid1448 (Box 22, Cd Prago 1-2, Box 80, Cassette 311 A-B)
    Interview by Don Amter.
  - William Preston, Aug 10, 1983; cuid1449 (Box 76, Cassette 197 A-B, Box 22, Cd Preston 1-2)
    Preston describes the University of Wisconsin during the early 1950s, the impact of William Appleman Williams and others on historical studies, the Madison social and political milieu, his research on Industrial Workers of the World, and his experiences as a historian.
  - Timo Puropudas, Jul 31, 1983; cuid1450 (Box 22, Cd Puropudas 1, Box 6, Cassette 196)
    Puropudas, Buhle, and an unidentified man discuss Puropudas' Finnish background, his role as editor of Tyomies since 1970s, attitudes towards the status and future of ethnic presses, and Puropudas' life as recent immigrant. The recording also contains a brief segment of Buhle interviewing an unidentified woman who recounts a story of Finnish farmers being cheated by a land agent.
  - Paul Andreas Rasmussen, 1973-1974; cuid1451 (Box 8, Folder 20, Box 23, Cd Rasmussen 1-10, Box 76, Cassette 198 A-I)
    Rasmussen discusses his political background in the Illinois Socialist Party and Workers Alliance during the late 1920s/early 1930s, his activities within Socialist Party, the formation of the Socialist Workers Party, and expulsion from Socialist Workers Party in 1947.
    Interview by Rich Klimmer.
    Duration: 486 minutes in nine parts
  - Paul Andreas Rasmussen, Apr 3, 1984; cuid1452 (Box 23, Cd Rasmussen 11-13, Box 76, Cassette 198 J-L)
    Interview includes discussion of Rasmussen's political background in Illinois, the Socialist Party and Workers Alliance during the late 1920s through early 1930s, activities within Socialist Party and formation of Socialist Workers Party, and expulsion from Socialist Workers Party in 1947. It also includes a discussion of the Communist Party and conflict between its working class and intellectual elements.
    Duration: 168 minutes in three parts
  - Paul Andreas Rasmussen, 1971; cuid1453 (Box 23, Cd Rasmussen 14-28, Box 76, Cassette 198 M-Y)
    Autobiographical narrative.
  - George Rawick, Oct 4, 1984; cuid1454 (Box 76, Cassette 199 A-B, Box 8, Folder 21, Box 23, Cd Rawick 1-2)
    Interview covers Rawick's family background, his adolescence in Brooklyn, experience around the Young Communist League and the Henry Wallace movement during the late 1940s, expulsion and attraction to the Shachtmanite movement, his activities during the 1950s, and the influence of the Shachtmanites on the New Left.
  - Philip Raymond, Oct 22, 1982; cuid1455 (Box 23, Cd Raymond 1-2, Box 76, Cassette 200 A-B)
    Interview covers the activities of the Auto Workers Union during the 1920s through the early 1930s, the political scene in Detroit, and the ethnic communities of auto workers.
  - Rose Raynes, Mar 21, 1979; cuid1456 (Box 23, Cd Raynes 1, Box 76, Cassette 201)
    Raynes discusses the founding and activities of the Emma Larazus Federation and the International Workers Order during the 1930s.
  - Ernie Reymer, Feb 16, 1978; cuid1457 (Box 10, Cassette 404 A-B, Box 23, Cd Reymer 1-2)
    Interview regarding International Workers Order.
  - George and Al Ribak, Apr 1, 1967; cuid1458 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    Interview contains the recollections of two long-time former Socialist Party activists, including a description of the activities of the Bridgeport, Connecticut Socialist Party from the 1910s-1940s
  - Harvey Richards, Nov 5, 1983; cuid1459 (Box 76, Cassette 203 A-B, Box 23, Cd H. Richards 1-2)
    Interview covers labor activity in the 1930s-1950s, radical film-making from early 1960s, early work with the Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee (SNCC), and use of film as educational/fundraising tool. Richard also discusses making films about destruction of redwood trees and the Bay Area Vietnam protest movement.
  - Paul Richards, Nov 15, 1983; cuid1460 (Box 76, Cassette 204, Box 23, Cd P. Richards 1)
    Richards discusses his Bay Area background and contrasts the multi-racial, working class Left of Oakland, California with the middle class, largely white community Madison, Wisconsin. He also covers his activities as an open Communist in Madison during the late 1960s, his departure from Communist Party, observations about student Left, reflections on life since.
  - Minnie Rivkin, Apr 7, 1980; cuid1461 (Box 76, Cassette 205, Box 23, Cd Rivkin 1)
    Rivkin discusses the Yiddish Chorus and broader Yiddishkayt from the 1930s-1980s.
  - Lester Rodney, Dec 29, 1981; cuid1462 (Box 23, Cd Rodney 1-3, Box 10, Cassette 423 A-C)
    Rodney discusses radicalism, sportswriting for the Daily Worker from the 1930s, and sports during the Cold War.
  - Amelia Romano, Dec 2, 1982; cuid1463 (Box 23, Box 10, Cassette 426)
    Interview documents Romano's involvement in left-wing theater, particularly in the 1930s. Organizations discussed include the Group Theatre, the Federal Theatre, and the Theatre of Action.
    Interview by Beth Friend.
  - I.A. Ronch, Apr 14, 1980; cuid1464 (Box 76, Cassette 207 A-F, Box 8, Folder 23, Box 23, Cd Ronch 1-5)
    Ronch discusses political and cultural life in Allerton Avenue Coops in the Bronx from the 1920s-1950s, cultural life inside Yiddish-speaking sector of Communist Party, his role as leader of Jewish People's Chorus during the 1950s, and cultural and poetic activities in Los Angeles during the 1960s-1970s.
  - Nina Rosenberg, Mar 14, 1983; cuid1465 (Box 8, Folder 24, Box 23, Cd N. Rosenberg 1-4, Box 76, Cassette 208 A-D)
    Rosenberg discusses the Yiddish cultural movement in Miami Beach from the 1940s-1980s.
  - Sadie Rosenberg, Jan 11, 1979 - Jan 15, 1979; cuid1466 (Box 8, Folder 25, Box 24, Cd S. Rosenberg 1-2, Box 76, Cassette 209 A-D)
    Rosenberg discusses her youth and family life during the 1920s, the International Workers Order, the Trade Union Unity League, Young Communist League's activities in Brooklyn during the 1930s-1940s, the United Electrical Workers Local 427 at Solar Manufacturing Company in Bayonne, New Jersey during the 1940s.
  - Sadie Rosenberg, Oct 31, 1979; cuid1467 (Box 8, Folder 26, Box 24, Cd Rosenberg 3-5, Box 4, Cassette 209 E-H)
    Rosenberg discusses her family background and early life.
  - Paul Rosencrantz, Jan 15, 1981; cuid1468 (Box 76, Cassette 210 A-B, Box 24, Cd Rosencrantz 1-2)
    Interview covers the activities of the Communist Party, the National Maritime Union, and factory organizing in New York and in Maine.
    Duration: 92 minutes
  - Florence Rossi, Mar 17, 1982; cuid1469 (Box 76, Cassette 211, Box 24, Cd Rossi 1-2)
    Interview documents the activities of the Hunter College Socialist Party and the broader Socialist Party during the 1930s.
  - Dan Rubel, Apr 12, 1976; cuid1470 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    Rubel discusses activities at the Jefferson School of Social Science and the impact of the Cold War.
  - Annette Rubenstein, Oct 17, 1976; cuid1471 (Box 24, Cd Rubinstein 1-3, Box 8, Folder 28, Box 76, Cassette 213 A-D)
    Discussion of literary environment and cultural criticism in the 1930s. Topics include: Masses and Mainstream, the Jefferson School, Realism as dominant style, disagreements between writers and Communist Party, the Party's role in 1930s America, detective stories, and drama. Writers discussed include: Dashiell Hammet, Leane Zugsmith, Ernest Hemingway, Alfred Maltz, Howard Fast, Mike Gold, Richard Wright, and Meridel Le Sueur. The interview heavily focuses on the outlook and intellectual currents of the Left in the 1930s, and some contrasts with the New Left are examined.
  - Annette Rubenstein, Dec 18, 1980; cuid1472 (Box 8, Folder 29, Box 76, Cassette 214, Box 24, Cd Rubinstein 4)
    Interview covers Rubinstein's Long Island background and her political and union activities during the 1930s. These activites include the People's Mobilization, the American Labor Party, and day care and birth control informational campaigns. Rubinstein also discusses the School for Democracy and Jefferson School during the 1940s-1950s and the effects of McCarthyism.
  - Annette Rubenstein, 1981; cuid1473 (Box 24, Cd Rubinstein 5, Box 8, Folder 30, Box 4, Cassette 213 D)
    Rubinstein describes joining the Communist Party, the activities of the American Labor Party activities, Mike Quill, the Jefferson School, leaving the Communist Party, and her life from the 1950s-1980s.
  - Annette Rubenstein, Mar 9, 1993; cuid1474 (Box 24, Cd Rubenstein 6, Box 80, Cassette 326)
    Interview regarding National Council of American-Soviet Friendship.
  - Joe Rudiak, Jun 28, 1983; cuid1475 (Box 24, Cd Rudiak 1-5, Box 76, Cassette 215 A-D)
    Rudiak describes life in small industrial-town Pennsylvania during the 1920s-1930s, his union activities and Left affiliation, electoral campaign and red-baiting during the 1930s, life in Pittsburgh, and work in fraternal societies.
  - Joe Rudiak, Peter Muselin, and Bernard Luketich, Jun 29, 1983; cuid1476 (Box 24, Cd Rudiak/Muselin/Luketich 1-3, Box 76, Cassette 215 D-E)
    Nature and activity of the Croatian Fraternal Union, changes since the 1920s, the emergence of "progressive" leadership during the 1940s-1950s, and service to the membership. He also discusses the organization's insurance and cultural activities in 1980s.
  - Julia Ruuttila, Sep 7, 1972; cuid1477 (Box 8, Folder 31)
    Interview covers the activities of the Industrial Workers of the World in Oregon and Washington during the 1910s.
  - Kirkpatrick Sale, Oct 8 - Oct 11, 1969; cuid1478 (Box 76, Cassette 217, Box 24, Cd Sale 1-2)
    Recording is comprised of Kirkpatrick Sale's daily reactions to the Days of Rage protests in Chicago during October of 1969, which included the Students for a Democratic Society, Weathermen, Revolutionary Youth Movement (RYM), and Young Lords. Includes Sale's daily accounts, and segments from news reports that Sale recorded alongside his own interpretations of the events. Sale offers detailed descriptions of protester tactics and the clashes between protesters and the police.
  - William Santora, Jul 25, 1980; cuid1479 (Box 24, Cd Santora 1-2, Box 76, Cassette 218 A-B)
    Santora describes early life in Jersey City, work at Emerson Radio New York, United Electrical Workers staff members helping to organize Federal Telephone and Telegraph, experience at the Westinghouse Elevator Company in New Jersey, and influence of the Left.
  - Sophie Saroff, May 15, 1979; cuid1480 (Box 24, Cd Saroff 1-4, Box 77, Cassette 220 A-B)
    Recording of Sophie Saroff's 80th birthday party.
  - Sophie Saroff, Dec 14, 1979; cuid1481 (Box 77, Cassette 219 A-E, Box 24, Cd Saroff 5-9, Box 8, Folder 32)
    Transcript available, Box 2; Index available
    Interview covers Saroff's family background in Russia, the 1905 Revolution in Russia, the Rand School of Social Science, the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU), Camp Unity, and the International Labor Defense during the 1930s.
    Per Saroff's request, a portion of the interview, representing audio that was lost between transcription and donation to the Oral History of the American Left, is read from the transcript.
    Interview by Arthur Tobier.
  - Finley Schaef, May 5, 1997; cuid1482 (Box 25, Cd Schaef 1-3, Box 10, Cassette 428 A-C)
    This interview with Reverend Finley Schaef of the Park Slope United Methodist Church chronicles his role as a leader in various movements on the Left in the late 20th century. These include the Viet Nam War anti-war movement, the abortion rights movement, the civil rights movement, and support for revolutionaries in Cuba, Nicaragua, and El Salvador.
    Interview by Janet Greene.
  - Daniel Boone Schirmer, Mar 18, 1981; cuid1483 (Box 77, Cassette 221 A-B, Box 25, Cd Schirmer 1-2)
    Topics covered include the National Students' League and the Congress of Industrial Organizations (CIO).
  - Chaim Schwartz, Dec 29, 1981; cuid1484 (Box 77, Cassette 223, Box 25, Cd Chaim Schwartz 1)
    Schwartz describes his activity as a Yiddish poet and Yiddish cultural circles from the 1930s-1980s.
  - Charles Schwartz, Apr 21, 1984; cuid1485 (Box 77, Cassette 222 A-B, Box 25, Cd Charles Schwartz 1-2)
    Interview covers Schwartz's background in Fall River from the 1950s-1960s, his high school radicalization, life and politics in Madison, Wisconsin in the late 1960s, experiences being down and out in California, his return to New England, and his activities in Left from the 1970s-1980s.
  - Pete Seeger, Feb 25, 1981; cuid1486 (Box 77, Cassette 224, Box 25, Cd Seeger 1)